Prashant Khatri

Senior Technical Support Engineer

CONTACT INFORMATION

Email: max29aug@hotmail.com

Address: Plot No: 118 Aravalli Vihar, Jamdoli, Agra Road Jaipur

Phone: +919929304211 Date of birth: Aug 29, 1995 **Nationality: Indian**

Social links, website: www.linkedin.com/in/prashant-khatri-710a731b6

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Support Engineer with 7+ years of expertise in virtual machines, Active Directory, DNS, VMware ESXi, Hyper-V, and Linux systems, currently advancing skills in AWS and Azure to pursue opportunities in Infrastructure as a Service (laaS).

EXPERIENCE

Pune, Maharashtra Aug 2023 - Present

Sr. Technical Support Engineer

Aloha Technology PVT LTD

- Design, implement and support enterprise-wide Active Directory and supporting systems.
- · Helped third party client with the troubleshooting for Active Directory Domain Services which includes support AD DS Replication, IP based networking, AD DS Integrated DNS records and zones, Site to subnet mapping, Kerberos Delegation, Windows Time Synchronization (NTP-Network Time Protocol), Group Polices based on LSDOU, Transfer and Seizure of FSMO Roles, Kerberos Authentication, Domain Controller Promotion and Demotion, Active Directory Backup, Domain Controller Defragmentation, Setup User Profiles (Local and Roaming User Profiles), DFSR and FSR including DFSR migration, Account Lockout, whitelisting and port blocking using Windows Server Firewall.
- Creating virtual machines using Hyper-V, VMware Player and VMware Fusion. Deploying virtual machines using Hyper-V, Third Party Deploying cloud services, Windows Deployment Services, Microsoft Deployment Kit.
- · Using WSUS and SCCM for deploying updates and configuring end point devices.
- · Deployed applications, updates, Operating System -Windows client OS, custom apps and custom scripts with the help of Cloud based SaaS model.

Jaipur, Rajasthan Feb 2022 - Mar 2023

AD DS Support Engineer

Resources Valley PVT LTD

- · Design, implement and support enterprise-wide Active Directory and supporting systems.
- · Helped third party client with the troubleshooting for Active Directory Domain Services which includes support AD DS Replication, IP based networking, AD DS Integrated DNS records and zones, Site to subnet mapping, Kerberos Delegation, Windows Time Synchronization (NTP-Network Time Protocol), Group Polices based on LSDOU, Transfer and Seizure of FSMO Roles, Kerberos Authentication, Domain Controller Promotion and Demotion, Active Directory Backup, Domain Controller Defragmentation, Setup User Profiles (Local and Roaming User Profiles), DFSR and FSR including DFSR migration, Account Lockout, whitelisting and port blocking using Windows Server Firewall.
- Creating virtual machines using Hyper-V, VMware Player and VMware Fusion.
- Implemented Organizational Unit (OU)-based delegation in Active Directory Users and Computers (ADUC) for Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR), user password resets, and account unlocks, enhancing service desk efficiency and security.

Gurgaon, Haryana

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Senior Technician, Technical Support

Dell Technologies

- Provided technical assistance and diagnosing faults in the running software on customer's computers, guiding customers with the solution. Closing tickets by proper guidance and feedback.
- · Helped worldwide customers using Dell Laptops, All-in-ones, printers, desktops and virtual machines.
- · Worked on Alienware laptops including hardware and software troubleshooting, Alienware Command Centre, Dell Digital Delivery, Dell Digital Locker, VMware Fusion and Built-in Self Tests for Dell products.
- · Windows consumer and commercial troubleshooting including Windows 11 and Windows Server 2022.
- · Supported clients with Microsoft Office Products, outlook configuration and remote support for gaming laptops and peripherals (including mini-port and port drivers).
- · Integrating Active Directory Domain Services with Esxi using DNS Records and Kerberos Authentication.
- Implemented Organizational Unit (OU)-based delegation in Active Directory Users and Computers (ADUC) for Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR), user password resets, and account unlocks, enhancing

Jaipur, Rajasthan

Dec 2018 - Mar 2021

Technical Support Executive

Teleperformance

- · Provided technical assistance and diagnosing faults in the running software on customers computer, guiding customers with the solution. Closing tickets by proper guidance and feedback.
- · Helped worldwide customers using Laptops, All-in-ones, printers, desktops and virtual machines,
- software and hardware support through chat, email and call as an international support executive. Worked on Gpedit, Windows Registry, Windows Updates, Windows Upgrade and Microsoft Office.
- · Windows consumer and commercial troubleshooting including Windows 10, Windows 7, Windows 8.1, Windows 8 and Windows Server 2016.
- · Supported clients with Microsoft Office Products, outlook configuration and remote support for gaming laptops and peripherals (including mini-port and port drivers).
- Implemented Organizational Unit (OU)-based delegation in Active Directory Users and Computers (ADUC) for Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR), user password resets, and account unlocks, enhancing service desk efficiency and security.

Jaipur, Rajasthan Apr 2016 - Oct 2018

Service Desk Analyst

Mobizweb PVT LTD

- · Helped company employees with the support for Laptops, All-in-ones, printers, desktops and virtual machines, software and hardware support.
- Worked on Gpedit, Windows Registry, Windows Updates, Windows Upgrade and Microsoft Office. Windows consumer and commercial troubleshooting including Windows 10, Windows 7, Windows 8.1,
- Windows 8 and Windows Server 2016. · Supported internal employees with Microsoft Office Products, outlook configuration and remote support
- for laptops, desktops and peripherals (including mini-port and port drivers). · Implemented Organizational Unit (OU)-based delegation in Active Directory Users and Computers (ADUC) for Self-Service Password Reset (SSPR), user password resets, and account unlocks, enhancing
- service desk efficiency and security

EDUCATION

Jaipur, Rajasthan Apr 2013 - Jun 2014

Jaipur, Rajasthan

Apr 2011 - Apr 2012

SKILLS

English Advanced

LANGUAGES

Customer service

DHCP

Senior Secondary Education

Cambridge Court High School

Cambridge Court High School

Secondary Education

Active Directory Domain Services Office 365 consumer based troubleshooting **Windows Server Backup and Recovery**

WDS MECM Azure (laas) **Problem-Solving DNS**

Windows Server Based troubleshooting Hyper-V

WSUS Microsoft Deployment Toolkit

AWS (laas)

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Introduction to Cloud by IBM:

https://courses.yl-ptech.skillsnetwork.site/certificates/52efc49b8c7b47db8947a2a88bf7944f **Networking Essentials by CISCO:**

https://www.credly.com/badges/ece74605-1210-4766-b67e-6963e1165228/public_url **Diploma in Computer Networking:**

https://cdn01.alison-static.net/parchment-previews/e15858ac2bf06647f7d848dd5ce4347c.jpg

Master MCSE: Windows Server 2022 OS Administration Course (Udemy): https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-594bc544-ed77-4f0b-8ba9-03d218c50287/

LFS101: Introduction to Linux:

https://www.credly.com/badges/93a9f7fc-9d30-4297-b927-cb6f0ecabc6c/public_url

AWS Knowledge - Cloud Essentials:

https://www.credly.com/badges/3458790b-9827-4e3f-b3a5-f2be8c44b98e/public_url Simplilearn - Cloud Architect (AWS & Azure):

https://success.simplilearn.com/259c84b7-d391-406d-8807-a797bf6ead97#acc.H8TNX1Lt

complete and true to the best of my knowledge.

SELF-DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the details and information given above are

PRASHANT KHATRI